我叫巴里·艾伦  是现今世上速度最快的人
My name is Barry Allen, and I am the fastest man alive.
我年幼时  看到自己的母亲
When I was a child, I saw my mother killed
被令人难以置信的东西杀害
by something impossible.
快跑  巴里
Run, Barry, run!
我父亲因为谋杀母亲进了监狱
My father went to prison for her murder.
但是一场事故让我也变得令人难以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但我秘密地用自己的速度打击犯罪
but secretly, I use my speed to fight crime
寻找跟我一样的人
and find others like me.
终有一天  我会找到杀害母亲的凶手
And one day, I'll find who killed my mother...
妈妈
Mom!
让我父亲沉冤得雪
And get justice for my father.
我就是  闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on The Flash...
如果你爱我
If you love me,
就告诉我你到底有什么事
you'll tell me what is going on with you.
不让她知道就能保证她的安全
Keeping her in the dark keeps her safe.
我不同意
I don't agree.
哈里森·威尔斯就是逆闪电
Harrison Wells is the Reverse-Flash.
十五年前  我和哈里森交情深厚
15 years ago, Harrison and I were thick as thieves.
我们都是前途无量的年轻科学家
We were promising young scientists,
泰丝去世后  一切都变了
and then everything changed after Tess died.
-你是谁  -我叫艾尔伯德·斯旺
- Who are you? - My name is Eobard Thawne.
在2020年  你和你妻子
In the year 2020, you and your wife
成功发射了粒子加速器
successfully launched a particle accelerator
改变了历史的进程
that changed the course of history.
我要想回去  要需要它早点发射
I need it to happen a bit sooner if I'm going to get back.
那天之后
After that day,
哈里森·威尔斯完全变成了另外一个人
Harrison Wells became a completely different person.
我的速度在变快  越来越快
I'm getting faster, faster than I've ever been,
我想  这是不是因为最近有什么在追我
and I wonder if it's because lately something's chasing me.
海滨城
我知道是什么在追我
I know what it is that's stalking me.
是我的过去
It's my past.
它越来越近了  速度与我相当
It's getting closer, and as fast as I am,
我不禁觉得我的过去
I can't help but feel like my past
马上就要赶上我了
has almost caught up with me.
巴里在哪
Where's Barry?
他应该马上就到了
He should be here any second.
我叫他出去买...
I sent him out for...
披萨
Pizza!
-什么  -海滨城买来的
- What? - From Coast City?
号称是西部最棒的呢
Supposedly the best in the west.
我之前怎没想到过
Why did I not think of this before?
到爸爸这来
Come to papa.
凯瑟琳
Caitlin?
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
好吧  我们调查了哈里森·威尔斯六个月
Okay, six months of investigating Harrison Wells
结果还是毫无头绪
has led us nowhere,
所以我们要回到起点
so we're going back to the beginning
看能不能有所发现
to see what we can find out.
什么叫回到起点
What does that mean?
要旅行了  宝贝
Road trip, baby.
乔和西斯科要去星城
Joe and Cisco are going to go to Starling City.
星城  去干什么
Starling City? What for?
去调查十五年前
To investigate the car accident
威尔斯博士和泰丝·摩根卷入的那场车祸
that Dr. Wells was in with Tess Morgan 15 years ago.
我不明白  调查车祸干什么
I-I don't understand. Why?
麦吉博士说威尔斯出事后
Dr. McGee said that after Wells's accident,
就像变了一个人似的
he became like a complete stranger.
和以前完全不一样了
Just a different person entirely.
因为他一生所爱死了呗
Because the love of his life died?
你应该比所有人都清楚
You of all people can understand
悲痛会怎样改变一个人
how grief can change a person.
凯特琳  我们认为威尔斯博士是逆闪电
Caitlin, we believe that Dr. Wells is the Reverse-Flash
是他杀了巴里的母亲
and killed Barry's mother,
也许泰丝·摩根也死在他的手下
and he may have done the same thing to Tess Morgan.
我们必须尽可能多地了解那晚的情况
We have to learn everything we can about that night.
看能不能有所收获
See where it leads us.
你能帮我在威尔斯博士那打打掩护吗
Oh, um, can you cover for me with Dr. Wells?
你是说撒谎吗
You mean lie?
是啊
Yeah.
我需要透透气
I need some air.
凯瑟琳
Hey, Caitlin...
看起来凯瑟琳跟咱不是一伙儿的
Doesn't look like Caitlin's with us.
不  她是咱们的人  我会和她谈谈的
No, she's with us. I'll talk to her.
我们在这儿需要做什么吗
What do you want us to do here?
一切照旧
Business as usual while we're gone.
收到
Copy that.
我想祝你此去好运
Well, I want to wish you good luck over there,
但我也害怕你可能会发现的结果
but I'm also scared of what you might find.
恐惧是好事
Scared is a good thing.
恐惧让我们能存活下去
Scared keeps us alive.
你能开下门吗  妮娜
Can you get the door, Nina?
妮娜
Nina?
抱歉
Sorry.
迷失在自己的小宇宙中了
Wrapped up in my own little world.
加夜班呢
Late night?
我还有一个活儿  做完就走
Just one more thing to do before I make my escape.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
晚安
Night.
咱们再过一遍
So let's go over this again.
监控录像上的人是你吧
This is you on the surveillance footage, correct?
看起来是我
It looks like me.
但那不是我
But it's not me.
我昨晚提早下班了
I left work early yesterday.
不信你可以问我丈夫
Ask my husband.
录像不会撒谎  你的丈夫可就说不准了
Footage doesn't lie. Your husband might.
那真的不是我
That's not me.
没前科  没被捕过  连超速罚单都没有
No priors, no arrests, not even a speeding ticket.
而且所有认识这个女人的人
And everyone who knows this woman,
同事  邻居
coworkers, neighbors,
都说她很亲切  和蔼
say she's the kindest, nicest,
是他们见过最诚实的女人
most honest woman they've ever met.
所以  除非她今早起来
So, unless she woke up this morning
心血来潮想犯罪
and out of nowhere decided to become a criminal--
也许我们要找的是一个超能力者
Maybe we should be looking for a meta-human.
没错
Yeah.
一个可以控制他人思想的人
One that can control people's minds.
强迫他们进行盗窃
Coerce them into becoming thieves.
这有可能吗
Is that possible?
你真问得出来
Is that a real question?
巴里
Hi, Barry.
你看到我爸了吗
Have you, um, seen my dad?
辛格队长说他请了几天假
Captain Singh says he took a couple of days off,
但他没回家
and he hasn't been home.
我没问过他
I didn't ask.
看来他是去休假了
Apparently he's taking a couple of personal days.
有其父必有其女吧
Like father, like daughter I guess.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你什么时候回家
When are you coming home?
感觉那里是家时再回
When it starts to feel like a home again.
你最好祈祷乔和西斯科
You better pray Joe and Cisco
在事故现场发现关于威尔斯的线索  巴里
find something on Wells at that accident site, Barry,
因为我已经无法再对爱瑞丝撒谎了
because I am just about done lying to Iris.
关于所有这一切的谎
About all of this.
好吧
Yeah.
我最近继承了这一整套
I recently inherited the entire collection.
漂亮
Beautiful.
让我去拿一下显微镜
Let me grab my microscope.
好的
Of course.
这里是911
911. Emergency.
我是阿伯特珠宝行的多米尼克
This is Dominic over at Abbott Jewelers.
有个人在我这出售被盗的钻石
I've got a guy in here trying to sell stolen diamonds.
早上好
Good morning.
我们能谈谈昨晚的事吗
Look, uh... can we talk about last night?
有什么好谈的
There's nothing to talk about.
当然需要谈  凯特琳
Yeah, there is actually. Caitlin, look,
我知道威尔斯博士为我们做了这么多
I know after everything Dr. Wells has done for all of us,
你一时间很难接受
it's hard to wrap your head around this,
但你得看清真相
but I need you to see the truth.
真相
The truth?
真相是他救过你很多次
The truth is that he saved your life multiple times.
我知道  但如果我没错的话
Look, I know. But if I'm right about this--
如果  巴里  如果
If, Barry, if.
在我相信这一切之前
And before I can believe any of this,
我需要看到证据
I'm gonna need to see some proof.
证据
Proof?
什么的证据
Proof of what?
我们可能又有一件超能力者的案子要处理
we may have another meta-human case on our hands.
我们随时乐意帮忙  巴里
We are always happy to help, Barry, as you know.
你们看见西斯科了吗  他还没来
Have you heard from Cisco? He hasn't arrived yet.
他得去帮他哥哥丹堤
Uh, he has to help Dante, his brother.
他可能要请几天假
He might need a few days off.
好
Ah, well.
好吧
All right.
艾迪
Eddie.
我接到报警电话说有人在卖
Hey, I got a call about a guy selling some of the jewelry
昨晚银行被盗的珠宝
stolen from the bank last night.
可能是银行职员的同伙
Could be the teller's partner.
他可能认出我了
I think he's made me.
我需要闪电侠的帮助
I could use The Flash's help.
马上到
Be right there.
你跑不过我的
You can't outrun me.
我用不着
I won't have to.
这个倒是新鲜
Well, that was new.
闪电侠
第一季  第十九集
变形人
A shape-shifter?
是啊  我亲眼看到一个大男人
Yeah, I literally saw a grown man, like,
变成一个少女
m--morph into a teenage girl.
很奇幻
That's fascinating.
当今的物理学家一直以来
Today's physicists have always regarded
都只认为可编程物质只存在于理论中
programmable matter as nothing more than a theory,
但你看到的变形人证明了这是可以实现的
but I guess your shape-shifter proves it can be done.
等等  所以不管他是男是女
Wait, so he, or she, or I--whatever.
这人真的可以转变成任何他触碰过的人吗
This person can actually transform into anyone they touch?
是的  看起来是这样
Yes, it appears so.
他也可以变成你  艾伦先生
That includes you, Mr. Allen.
威尔斯博士说得对
Dr. Wells is right.
如果你以闪电侠的身份被他碰到
If you are touched while you're the Flash,
而他转变成你的话
and he transforms into you,
面具下你的真实身份
we run the risk of him exposing
就很有可能暴露
that Barry Allen is the man behind the mask.
现在我们还不知道
Because at this point we don't know
变形人是否能吸收除了外表以外
if the shape-shifter is capable of absorbing more
其他特征的能力
that just your physical characteristics.
比如说  他可能可以复制我的速度
Like he might be able to copy my speed?
那就不妙了
That would be bad.
明白了  别碰超能力者
Got it. Hands off the meta-human.
别碰超能力者
Hands off the meta-human.
那我们要怎么找到
So how do we find someone
一个可以变成任何人的人
who can transform into anyone?
就像其他难题一样
We , I guess like any problem,
我们回到起点
you just go back to the beginning.
在这个案子中  也就是要找到变形人
In this case, that would mean finding the first person
在发现自己的超能力时
the shape-shifter morphed into
首次转变成的人
when they discovered their powers.
是啊  你能调出中城警局记录中
Yeah, can you pull up the CCPD records
被摄像头拍到犯罪事实
of cases where the perpetrator plead innocent,
却声称自己是无辜的那些人的
even though they were caught on camera
所有案子吗
committing the crime?
你很厉害  巴里·艾伦
You're good, Barry Allen.
你真厉害
You're very good.
看看这个  很多这类案件
Look at this. Multiple crimes of this manner
都发生在
all dating back to a month
粒子加速器爆炸后一个月
after the particle accelerator explosion.
第一起是
And the first one was?
雅各布·费舍尔
Jacob Fisher.
联合信贷联盟的职员
A teller at the Federal Credit Union.
声称他是无辜的  被他最好的朋友
Claims he was innocent, and was framed by his best friend,
案件综述
汉尼拔·贝茨陷害
a Hannibal Bates.
我把这个消息传给中城警局
I'll pass this along to the CCPD,
汉尼拔·贝茨
看他们能否追踪到他
see if they can track him down.
很好
Good.
谢谢你  威尔斯博士
Thank you, Dr. Wells.
随时乐意帮你  巴里
Always here to help, Barry.
星城
星城中央警局
就这个
There it is.
这就是全部资料吗
This is all you have?
这案子很简单  警探
Well, it's a pretty cut and dry case, Detective.
哈里森·威尔斯  泰丝·摩根
Harrison Wells, Tess Morgan
周日开车去兜风
are out on a Sunday drive,
车胎爆了  威尔斯失去了控制
the tires blow, Wells loses control,
可悲的是泰丝当场死亡
and, uh...sadly Tess dies on the scene.
要一直背负那种负罪感真是难以想象
Couldn't imagine carrying that kind of guilt around.
你俩想找什么
So, uh...what are you two hoping to find?
我们还不确定
We're not exactly sure yet.
你们大老远从中城跑来
You come all the way from Central City,
竟然不知道要找什么
you don't know what you're looking for?
只是凭直觉
Just following a hunch.
你能带我们去事故现场吗
Uh, can you take us to the accident site?
已经十五年了
It's been 15 years.
我看照片更能帮上忙
I think the pictures will serve you better.
我们还是希望能去看看
Still, we'd appreciate a look.
随便你们吧
Whatever you need.
队长  我需要乔书亚·布朗案的
Captain, I need those witness statements
证人证言
for the Joshua Brown trial.
好  我跟你说过了  晚点吧
Um, yeah, well, like I told you, end of day.
抱歉  韦斯特警探  西斯科·拉蒙
Sorry, uh, Detective West, Cisco Ramon,
这位是助理地方检察官劳蕾尔·兰斯
this is A.D.A. Laurel Lance.
是你亲戚吗
Related?
女儿
Daughter.
你好啊
Hey there.
你和巴里·艾伦
You work at S.T.A.R. Labs
一起在尖端科研实验室工作  对吧
with Barry Allen, right?
是啊
Uh, yeah.
我能私下跟你谈谈吗
Can I talk to you privately for a minute?
当然可以
Sure.
艾伦怎么样了
So, uh...how is Allen?
但愿他没被那到闪电
Not too messed up from getting hit
劈得七荤八素
by that lightning, I hope.
没有
No, no.
你怎么认识巴里的
How do you know Barry?
你们是朋友吗
Are you guys, like, friends or something?
算不上
Not really.
上次他来星城见我的一些朋友时
We met last time he was in Starling City
我们见过
visiting my friends.
约翰·狄格尔  费利西蒂·斯莫克
John Diggle, Felicity Smoak,
以及奥利弗·奎恩
and Oliver Queen.
三个没有任何共同点的人
Three people who have absolutely nothing in common.
就我所知的来看
As far as I know.
西斯科  我知道巴里是闪电侠
Cisco, I know Barry's the Flash,
奥利弗是绿箭侠
and Oliver's the Arrow.
你怎么知道的
How do you know that?
因为我是黑金丝雀
Because I'm the Black Canary.
-别逗我了  -是真的
- Stop playing. - It's true.
快别逗我了
You stop it right now.
不是吧
No.
好了  好了  冷静点
Okay, okay. Calm down.
我爱你
I love you.
我是说  我爱你击败罪犯的方式
I mean, I love the way that you beat up criminals.
等等
Wait.
你为什么要告诉我这些
Why are you telling me this?
因为我需要一些专业技术
Because I need some technical expertise.
我一直在用我妹妹的声波装置
I've been using my sister's sonic device.
我希望你能帮我...
I was hoping you could help...
改装一下
modify it.
行  我想我已经有主意了
Yeah. I think I've got some ideas.
太好了
Great.
诺里斯就职报告
怎么  你在监视我吗
What--are you spying on me now?
凯特琳  你去威尔斯家干什么
Caitlin, what were you doing at Wells's house?
我要跟他谈谈  问他一些问题
I was gonna talk to him and get some answers of my own.
不行  你不能跟他谈
You can't. You cannot talk to him.
难道我就应该站在那里
Oh, so I'm just supposed to stand by
看着你们所有人毁了这个人的生活吗
and watch all of you ruin this man's life?
毁了我的生活吗
Ruin my life?
你说"你的生活"是什么意思
What are you talking about "Your life?"
你昏迷的那九个月里
Those nine months that you were in a coma
是我人生最低潮的时期
were the worst of my life.
我失去了我的名誉  我的未婚夫
I lost my reputation, my fiance,
而在我经历这一切的时候
and through all of that,
哈里森·威尔斯一直陪在我身边
Harrison Wells stood by my side.
告诉我一切都会好起来的
He told me everything was going to be okay.
如果威尔斯博士是你所说的那个人
If Dr. Wells is who you say he is,
那么从我踏进尖端科研实验室的那刻起
everything I've done since the minute
所有发生的一切
I stepped foot in S.T.A.R. Labs
都是个谎言
has been a lie.
凯特琳
Caitlin.
如果我说的都是对的
If I am right about all of this,
而你却把现在发生的事都告诉了他
and you tell him what's been going on,
那我就永远无法把我爸从监狱里救出来了
I'll never be able to get my dad out of prison.
巴里
Barry.
就算不为了我  也为了他考虑一下
If not for me, just do it for him.
真不敢相信你把你爸爸搬出来了
I can't believe you're pulling the dad card.
那不公平  巴里
That's dirty pool, Barry.
那就等乔和西斯科回来再说
Just until Joe and Cisco get back.
拜托了
Please.
原来汉尼拔·贝茨失踪已经超过一年了
Turns out Hannibal Bates hasn't been seen in well over a year.
仅存的亲属只有他的祖母
Only remaining relative is his grandmother.
在雅各布·费舍尔被捕后
She took out a missing person's report
她向警方报告了他的失踪
a couple of days after the Jacob Fisher arrest.
也许我们能问她几个问题
Figure we could ask her a few questions.
比如在他的家人里面
Like why anyone in their family
为何没人认为给孩子起名汉尼拔
thought that naming a kid Hannibal
意味着他长大以后会成为一名罪犯
wouldn't mean he'd grow up to become a criminal?
您最近有您孙子汉尼拔的消息吗
Have you heard from your grandson, Hannibal, recently,
贝茨夫人
Mrs. Bates?
最近吗
Recently?
没有  为什么这么问
No. Why do you ask?
请坐
Oh, please.
因为你在一年前提交了
Because you filed a missing person's report
失踪人口报告
over a year ago.
是的  没错
Oh, yes, I certainly did.
你必须要原谅我  警探
You'll have to forgive me, Detective.
我的记性已经大不如前了
My memory is not quite as it used to be.
当然
Of course.
很明显  我的礼数也不太周全了
Uh, neither apparently are my manners.
你们想喝点什么
May I get you two something?
咖啡还是茶
Coffee, tea?
不用  谢谢  女士  我们不渴
Uh, no thank you, ma'am. We're fine.
拜托
Oh, please.
不会耽误太久的
It'll only take a minute.
我很高兴有人来探望我
It's nice to have visitors.
咖啡好了
Coffee'd be nice.
谢谢
Thanks.
女士  您有汉尼拔近期的照片吗
Ma'am, would you happen to have a recent photograph of Hannibal?
女士
Ma'am?
她不见了
She's gone.
我去前门
I'll take the front.
我们找到贝茨了
Hey, we located Bates.
他伪装成他祖母的样子
He was impersonating his grandma.
巴里  别让他碰你
Barry, do not let him touch you.
或者让他看到你用超能力
Or let him see you use your super speed.
那我怎么才能抓住他呢
Well, how am I supposed to catch him?
用传统办法
The old-fashioned way.
像个正常人一样跑
Run like a normal person.
好吧
Okay, all right.
老天
Oh, man.
需要我们做什么  斯旺
What do you want us to do, Thawne?
死
Die.
巴里  打911
Barry, call 911.
需要我们做什么  斯旺
What do you want us to do, Thawne?
死
Die.
我知道这看起来像什么  塞西尔
I know what this looks like, Cecile.
看起来就像你手下的一名警探
It looks like one of your detectives
枪击了两名警察
shot two of your cops,
这两个人现在还命悬一线
both of whom are now fighting for their lives.
事情不是那样的
That's not what happened.
大卫  我是地方检察官
David, I am the District Attorney.
我不能因为你的要求
I can't ignore what I just watched
就忽略刚才看到的一切
because you want me to.
我们都知道这城市里
We both know there are things going on
现在正发生着一些无法解释的事
in this city that can't be explained.
行了  大卫  在我看到确凿证据之前
Come on, David. Until you show me something
我能做的就只有向你保证
incontrovertible, the best that I can do
不让他进铁山监狱的牢房
is promise to keep him out of gen pop at Iron Heights.
你能解释这件事吗  艾伦
Do you have any way to explain this, Allen?
我在想办法
I'm working on it.
-巴里  -爱瑞丝
- Barry. - Iris.
怎么回事  中城时报的人都在说
What is going on? Everyone at CCPN is saying
艾迪枪击了两名警察
that Eddie shot two cops.
那怎么可能呢
How is that even possible?
我们还不确定
We're not sure yet.
你不会也认为是他做的吧
You don't think he did this, do you?
-不  当然不会  -我要见他
- No, of course not. - I need to see him.
你不能见他  知道吗
You can't-- you can't see him, all right?
他们不会让你见他的
They're not gonna let you. Look...
我会尽一切所能去帮助他的  好吗
I'm gonna do everything I can to help him. Okay?
好了  很抱歉
Okay, I'm so sorry.
会没事的
It's gonna be okay.
-好吧  -我保证
- Okay. - I promise.
好吗
All right?
肯定就是这里了
This is definitely the place.
西斯科  看看能找到什么
Cisco, let's see what we can find.
那是什么  金属探测仪吗
What is that? A, uh, metal detector?
差不多吧
Uh, essentially.
不过不是用来探测金属物质
Only instead of listening for metal objects,
而是用来探测
I'm listening for anything
能放射出异常声波的东西
that emits a abnormal sound wave.
好吧
Right.
你从哪找来的这个孩子
Where'd you find this kid?
说来话长
It's a long story.
有个做地方检察官的女儿
So, it must be interesting having a daughter
一定很有意思吧
who is also the D.A.
是啊  是挺有意思的
Yeah, interesting's the word.
-我也有个女儿  -是同行吗
- I have a daughter of my own. - Same line of work?
不  我绝不会让她接触这些不好的东西
No, I wouldn't let her anywhere near this nonsense.
很智慧
Smart guy.
是保护过度才对
Overprotective.
你俩关系好吗
You two get along?
虽然我们也不是总谈得来
We don't always see eye to eye,
但不管她多么生我的气
but no matter how mad she gets at me
或者我多么生她的气
or how mad I get at her,
毕竟血浓于水
there's a strong bond.
怎么
Why?
你们俩关系不太好吗
You two have a bit of a rough patch?
是啊  她...
Yeah, she, uh...
有些事情没告诉我
she kept something from me,
很重要的事
you know, something important.
瞒了我好几个月
Lied to me about it for months.
遇到这种事就很难和好了
Hard to come back from something like that.
她有解释吗
Mm. She give a reason?
没给出什么我能接受的解释
Not one I could accept.
有时我们说谎是出于爱
Ah. Well, sometimes we lie for love.
尤其是事关家人时  不是吗
Especially when it comes to family, right?
-乔  -哎
- Joe! - Yeah?
我想有发现了
I think we got something.
超光速粒子  时光穿梭产生的
Tachyons. Little bits of time travel.
确定吗
You sure?
很确定
Pretty sure, yeah.
我没向那些警员开枪
I didn't shoot those officers.
是啊  队长也是这么说的
Yeah, the Captain certainly plead your case.
火药残余测试的结果出来了
The results of the GSR swab.
斯旺警探的手上完全没有
Detective Thawne's hands are completely free
铅  钡或者锑残留
of lead, barium, and antimony.
但却没人能给我解释
Yet no one can seem to explain
为什么监控录像清楚地显示出
how the surveillance video clearly shows
斯旺开枪了的事实
Thawne firing his weapon.
他只是长得像斯旺警探而已
It only looked like Detective Thawne.
艾伦先生  请不要这样
Mr. Allen, no.
你作为科学家不更应该严谨行事吗
Aren't you supposed to be the scientist around here?
不能怪她  视频太清楚了
It's hard to blame her. That video is pretty damning.
不不  我们得说服她
No. No, we just have to convince her.
眼见为实  巴里
Seeing is believing, Barry.
他们只能把我关起来了
They're gonna put me away.
你去尖端科研实验室
Okay, look, you get to S.T.A.R. Labs.
他们会给你弄个一次性电话
They'll set you up with a burner phone.
-我去联系...  -不行
- I'll contact-- - No.
如果我现在逃跑  那监控录像
I run now, that surveillance video
就真不是大问题了
is the least of my problems.
我会显得更可疑
No way I don't smell guilty.
他们一定会开除我了
No way they'll let me stay on the force.
你自己也说了
Look, you said it yourself,
如果抓不到汉尼拔·贝茨
if we don't find Hannibal Bates,
你就得入狱
you go to prison.
为你没有犯下的罪行
For a crime you didn't commit.
我不会让这种事发生的  这次不会
I'm not gonna let that happen. Not again.
这次和你父亲那次不一样  巴里
This isn't like your dad, Barry.
艾迪  听着
Eddie, look.
你父亲被抓时
When you dad was put away,
你还是个孩子
you were a kid.
你什么事也做不了
There wasn't anything you could do.
但现在你不是孩子了
But you're not a kid anymore.
你是科学家
You're a scientist.
拜托  你就是闪电侠啊
Hell, you're The Flash.
你一定能找到贝茨
You are going to find Bates,
一定能为我正名
and you are going to clear me.
去吧
So go do it.
好吧
All right.
用正确的方式救我
Get me out of here the right way.
我保证  爱瑞丝
I promise, Iris.
我只是洗个澡换身衣服
Now, I'm just here to shower and change,
然后马上就回实验室
and then I'm going right back to my lab.
我保证我一定救艾迪出来  好吗
I swear I'm going to get Eddie out of this, okay?
再联系  好吗
I'll call you later, all right?
艾迪  怎么回事  你怎么出来的
Eddie? What in the world? How did you get out?
辛格队长找了点关系
Captain Singh called in a favor.
让法官释放了我
Got a judge to sign my release.
我刚还在跟爱瑞丝通话呢
I was just on the phone with Iris.
你怎么不联系她呀  稍等
Why haven't you called her? Hold on.
她谁啊
I have no idea who she is.
巴里  是我
Barry, it's me.
你  好
Hello... you.
我想我找到办法阻止变形人
I think I figured out a way to stop our shapeshifter
变换成别人的模样了
from morphing into other people.
真的吗
Oh, really?
我可以制造一种血清
What if I create a serum
终止聚合反应
that will terminate the polymerization reaction,
这样就能让基因链复原成初始形态
essentially forcing the bonds to revert to their original form
他就不能控制自己的力量了
stopping him from being able to control his power.
你能做到吗
You can do that?
-我觉得可以  -好吧
- Yeah, I think so. - Okay.
你怎么了
What's wrong with you?
没怎么啊
Nothing.
关于昨晚的事
Look, about last night,
我知道这对你来说也很不容易
I can't imagine how hard this must be for you.
我理解你有多么想
I mean, I know how desperate you are
解开你母亲的谋杀案
to solve your mom's murder.
但我们能不能先把这事放一边
But let's just bury the hatchet,
回到尖端科研实验室
and we'll go back to S.T.A.R. Labs.
想办法先对付这个任意人
Figure out how to catch this Everyman.
任意人
"Everyman?"
昵称不好吗
Bad nickname?
不
No.
我挺喜欢的
No, I kinda like it.
好吧  那就好  我也喜欢
Okay, good. Me, too.
等等  西斯科
Wait, hold up, Cisco.
请告诉我是我想错了
Please tell me that's not what I think it is.
好吧  那绝对是只手
Okay, that is definitely a hand.
好吧  其实我以为是脚
Okay, see, I thought it was a foot,
但手也一样糟糕啊
but a hand is just as bad.
这太恐怖了
That is freaky.
这是证据  西斯科
That is proof, Cisco.
得检测完才能确定
I'll need to test it to be certain.
我去拿工具箱
I'm gonna grab my kit.
我得叫警员来
Okay, I'm gonna have to call this one in.
我不能让你这么做
I can't let you do that.
我以同为警察的身份请求你
Now I'm asking you, cop to cop,
不要声张此事
keep this under wraps.
忘记你看到过这个
Forget you ever saw it.
-韦斯特  我不能  -听着  兰斯
- West, I can't do that. - Listen, Lance,
如果我的想法没错
if this is who I think it is,
那么知道此事的人
anybody that knows about this
都会处于危险之中
is in a hell of a lot of danger,
包括我女儿
including my daughter.
虽然你在生劳拉的气
As mad as you are at Laurel,
但我想你还是会尽力去保护她的
I can't imagine you wouldn't do anything to protect her.
可以啦
Hey. Good to go.
就是需要转一转了
Just need to give it a little spin.
对了  没错
Right. Yes.
转转
A spin.
那这个
So this, uh...
你制作的血清
serum that you're making,
只是暂时的吗
is it a temporary fix,
还是会让他永久性的失去超能力
or will it take away his power permanently?
不是永久性的
Not permanently.
只是为我们争取抓到他的时间
Just long enough so we can stop him.
还要多久才能做好
And how long is it going to take?
马上就好
Not long.
我们只需...
We just need--
你搞什么啊
What are you doing?
一件我认为我应该...
Something I think I should have done...
早就做了的事
a long time ago.
巴里  你...
Barry, uh...
天呐
Oh, my God.
瞧瞧谁来了
Look who's here.
她啊
Yes. Her.
我到处找你呢
Hi, I have been looking for you everywhere.
这不是找着了  怎么了
Here I am. What's up?
我想着  不论是谁栽赃了艾迪
Look, whoever is framing Eddie, I got to thinking.
他们以前也许也玩过同样的把戏
What if they've done something like this before?
我查阅了中城时报的罪案资料库
I went through CCPN's crime archives,
在过去的十一个月里  有六起案件的
and in the last 11 months, there have been six crimes
犯罪嫌疑人都宣称
committed by people who later swore
他们是无辜的
that they were innocent.
这些人都没有前科
None of them had priors,
而且都有可靠的不在场证明
all of them had rock-solid alibis.
-好吧  -所以...
- All right. - So...
我黑进了我爸在警局的账户
I hacked into my dad's CCPD account,
查看了艾迪枪杀那些警察的录像
and went through the footage of Eddie shooting those cops.
-看  -需要我们做什么  斯旺
- Look. - What do you want us to do, Thawne?
死
Die.
你俩怎么了
What's wrong with you?
没什么
Huh? Nothing.
我什么也没干啊
I didn't do anything.
我也说不好  看起来没啥疑点啊
I don't know. Seems pretty convincing to me.
你再仔细看看
Look again.
艾迪不是左撇子
Eddie is not left-handed.
他肯定是被陷害了  我们得找出
Look, Eddie is being framed, and we need to figure out
其中的幕后黑手
who is behind this.
相信我  等我抓到他们
And believe me, when I get my hands on them,
他们就...
they are going to be--
天呐  你做了什么
Oh, my God. What did you do?
你对枪手的观察非常敏锐  韦斯特小姐
Your observations about the shooter were spot on, Miss West.
他的确是左撇子
He was indeed left-handed.
这个人也是
As is this man.
而我们的巴里  是右撇子
Our Barry... is right-handed.
我就说嘛
Oh, I knew it.
-别理我  -那就是这个人了
- Never mind. - Then this is him.
没错
It is indeed.
我得押他去警局
I need to take him in to the police.
让警方见识下他的能力
If they can see what he can do,
说不定他们就会放了艾迪
then maybe they'll let Eddie go.
还是让我和斯诺博士处理此事吧
Perhaps it might be best if Dr. Snow and I handle this.
你俩要对他做什么
What are you two going to do?
不  不行  我要带他去投案
No. No, no, no. I'm taking him in.
好吧
Of course.
我陪你一起去吧
Well, at least let me help you.
我工作的地方有个记者有一份档案
There is a reporter at work who kept a file
都是关于这一类事情的
of these sorts of things.
你知道的  市里那些奇闻怪事
You know, all of the unexplained events in the city.
这个家伙...
This guy...
绝对应该列入那份档案
definitely belongs in that file.
那这份档案该有多厚重啊
That's gonna be a pretty big file.
你知道还有谁在里边吗
You know who else is in that file?
火人
The Burning Man.
是吗  他怎么了
Oh, really? What about him?
我以为他不过是个传说呢
I thought he was just some urban legend.
救命  救命  救救我
Help me! Help me, help me, help me!
-这下糟了  -来人呐  救我
- Oh, no. - Someone, please, help me!
救命  这俩坏人绑架了我
Help! Help! These bad ladies have kidnapped me!
-这怎么回事  -帮帮我
- What's going on here? - I need help!
救命啊  她俩绑架了我
I need help! These bad ladies kidnapped me!
我们没绑架她
We did not kidnap her.
-真没  -爱瑞丝  开车
- No. - Iris, drive.
-没法开啊  -快报警
- I can't. - Call the police.
别别  她很危险
No. No, no, no. She's dangerous.
她很危险  不
She's dangerous. No!
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
巴里
Oh, Barry.
你来真的啊
For real?
扇我干嘛
Why did you slap me?
因为你昏迷了
Because you were unconscious.
你让我嗅盐也行啊
Smelling salts work just as well.
抱歉  你还好吗
Sorry. You okay?
还行
I think so, yeah.
等等  凯特琳  贝茨刚在这儿
Wait, Caitlin. Bates, he was here.
是  我知道
Uh, yes, I know.
好  我们走
Okay, let's go.
星城警局
你确定不需要我帮忙了吗  警探
You sure there's nothing else I can do for you, Detective?
你做得够多了
You have done more than enough.
谢谢你的协助  队长
Thank you for everything, Captain.
是我该谢你
Listen, I should be thanking you
偶尔跑跑外勤也不错
for getting me out of the office for a day.
不用再审阅文件  预算
Pushing papers, reviewing budgets,
处理公共事务之类  换换脑子挺好
public all over my ass. It's been a nice change.
我挺想继续当警探的
I'd still be detective if I could, but, you know,
但身体撑不住啦
body just can't take it anymore.
没办法  心脏出了问题
What you gonna do when you got a bad heart?
我有个想法  或许能改变现状
I can think of something that might make things better.
西斯科
Cisco.
劳蕾尔
Laurel, hey.
我们正准备回中城呢
We're just about to head back to Central City.
那个东西你弄好了吗
Were you able to make that item?
都按你的要求改好了
I think this will do the trick.
我提升了各项数值
I bumped up the specs.
将传播范围扩大了四倍  共鸣增强了三倍
Quadrupled the range, tripled the resonance.
有了它  你一定大有可为
You should be able to do some serious damage with this thing.
没想到你这么快就能完成
I can't believe you were able to make it so quickly.
最近在声波上我做了不少研究
I've had some practice with sound waves recently.
不如就把它叫"雀吼"吧
I think you should call it "The Canary Cry."
我喜欢  谢谢
I like it. Thank you.
给  你的酬劳
As promised.
别给别人看  否则你死定了
Hey, you show this to anyone, I'll kill you.
你就是那么一说
That's just an expression,
对吧
right?
不是
Nope.
西斯科  准备好了吗
Cisco? You good?
好了
Oh, I'm good.
这个汉尼拔·贝茨可是个
So this Hannibal Bates has turned into
了不起的超能力者  你瞧
quite the meta-human. Take a look.
他的细胞能
His cells have the ability to transmogrify
快速变形
at quite the rate.
所以他能成为任何人
Which is how he can become anyone.
只是外表而已
Which is how he can look like anyone.
他没法复制你的记忆或能力
Because he cannot appropriate your memory or your powers.
懂了  碰到他没事
Got it. Hands on the meta-human.
没错  为了做到这一点
Hands on the meta-human. And to help you do that,
斯诺博士调制了一种制剂
Dr. Snow has concocted a solution we believe
可以扼制他的能力
will stop him.
对  我研制的血清可以
Yes. I've made a serum that will create
在他的细胞内引起皮质反应
a cortical reaction around his cells.
夺取细胞中的电荷
Deprive those cells of their electrical charge,
他也就不能变形了
his shape-shifting days are over.
你可真了不起
Wow, that's great work.
谢谢
Thank you.
保持距离
No need for a hug
什么亲亲抱抱的都不要有
or anything like that.
好吧
Okay.
巴里
Oh, Barry.
中城机场
警告  警报
我们收到你手机发来的脉冲信号
We got a ping from your cell phone.
看来汉尼拔·贝茨在机场
Looks like Hannibal Bates is at the airport.
是时候反击了
Payback time.
你们确定他在机场吗
Guys, are we sure he's at the airport?
你手机上的GPS是这么显示的  他就在那
According to the GPS on your phone, he's there.
没错  但是
Yeah, but...
他可以变身成任何一个人
he could be any of these people.
我没看到他
I'm not seeing him.
找到你了
Gotcha.
汉尼拔·贝茨
Hannibal Bates.
我想你认错人了
I think you've mistaken me for someone else.
等等  是我
Wait. It's me.
请别伤害我
Please don't hurt me.
真不像个英雄
Not so hero-like.
对你的女人都这么粗鲁吗
Treat all your women like that?
瞧瞧啊
Well, look at that.
我是闪电侠
I'm The Flash.
你看起来是像我
You may look like me...
可你的速度不够快
but you're not as fast.
你不能再模仿无辜的人了
You're done imitating innocent people.
-巴里  -在
- Barry? - Yeah.
独一无二的
The one and only.
斯旺警探已经被释放了
Detective Thawne has been released.
我不得不承认  这对我来说是新的领域
I have to admit this is new territory for me.
对我们所有的人来说都是新的领域
This is new territory for all of us.
我很肯定法律还不足以
I certainly don't think the law is prepared
判定这种罪犯的罪名
to deal with this kind of criminal.
希望我们能快点跟上脚步
Hopefully we can catch up fast.
难以置信我们生活在一个
It's hard to believe we live in a world
有奇迹存在的世界
where this kind of impossible even exists.
幸好这个世界同时也有闪电侠的存在
Luckily it's also a world where The Flash exists.
说到这个
Uh, speaking of...
他留下了这份
he left this list of all the robberies
汉尼拔·贝茨参与过的抢劫案名单
that Hannibal Bates was involved in.
这份名单不短啊
That's a long list.
无辜的人也不少啊
With just as many innocent people
需要撤销他们的罪名
whose names need to be cleared.
我见过闪电侠一次
You know, I saw The Flash once.
-是吗  -是
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
当时我正在去法院的路上
I was on my way to the courthouse.
他从我身边呼啸而过
He blew past me. It was...
只是一个红色模糊的影子和一阵狂风
it was just a blur of red and a gust of wind.
但是那真的酷得惊人
But it was pretty damn cool.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
所有的指控都撤销了
All charges have been dropped.
无罪释放
I'm clear to go.
感谢上帝
Oh, thank God.
爱瑞丝
Iris...
我有事要告诉你
I need to tell you something.
你知道吗  可以等我们到家再说
You know what? It can wait until we get home.
你说得对
You were right.
我的确有事瞒着你
I was hiding something from you,
你应该知道真相
and you deserve to know the truth.
我之所以最近对你这么冷淡
The reason I've been so distant lately...
是因为我一直在和闪电侠合作
I've been working with The Flash.
放我出去
Let me out of here!
小可爱  放我出去吧
Hey, cutie. Want to let me out of here?
好像有谁会蠢到相信他似的
Like anyone would be dumb enough to fall for that.
看你变了这么多样子
Seen a lot of things that you can become,
但你到底是谁  汉尼拔·贝茨
but who are you, Hannibal Bates?
我
I, uh...
我不记得了
I can't remember.
把门锁上吧  大家晚安
Well, let's lock up shop. Good night, everyone.
那威尔斯博士呢
What about Dr. Wells?
过来
Come here.
我要给你看点东西
I need to show you something.
这不可能
This isn't possible.
凯特琳  我做了两遍DNA测试
Caitlin, I ran the DNA test twice.
结果都是完美的匹配
It's a perfect match.
这具尸体是如假包换的哈里森·威尔斯
This body is the real Harrison Wells.
如果这是威尔斯博士
If this is Dr. Wells,
那一直和我们合作的人是谁
then who have we been working for this whole time?
麦吉博士说那场车祸之后
Dr. McGee said that after the accident,
威尔斯博士完全变成了另外一个人
Wells became a completely different person.
是因为他根本就是另外一个人
It's because he is a different person.
威尔斯博士
Dr. Wells.
你来是为了公事吗
You here on business?
公事  不是  我是来问候斯旺警探的
Business, no. I came to give my regards to Detective Thawne.
很高兴事情都解决了
Glad it all worked out.
是啊  对他来说真是疯狂的一天
Yeah. Crazy day for him.
没错
Yeah.
对我们来说也是
Crazy day for us all.
警探  你享受待在星城的日子吗
Detective, did you enjoy your time in Starling City?
没抽出什么时间观光
Not much time for sightseeing.
我是去办案的
I was working on a case.
你以前在那住过
You used to live there.
是的
I did.
有回去过吗
You ever go back?
没有
No.
那里有太多和苔丝有关的回忆了
Too many memories of Tess.
没错  抱歉
That's right. Sorry.
警探你  是我认识人当中少有的
You, Detective, are one of the few people I know that
真正明白那种失去之痛的人
truly understands that kind of loss.
爱瑞丝的母亲  你从不提起她  对吧
Iris's mother, you never talk about her, do you?
对
No.
从不提起
I don't.
是吗
No?
警探  我和你
You and I, Detective,
看来都是同属于一类之中的人
are members of a rather exclusive club, I suppose.
成为这类人要付出很大代价
One who's membership is too expensive.
也许我们有空时  该去喝一杯
Maybe we should have another drink sometime.
聊一下
Talk about it.
好
Yeah.
是  该去喝一杯
Yeah, we should do that.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
在粒子加速器爆炸后
After the accelerator exploded,
我做了一个尖端科研实验室的3D模型
I built a 3-D model of S.T.A.R. Labs
这样我就能查明引起故障的原因
so that I could pinpoint exactly what caused the malfunction.
你一直没检查过吗
And you never ran this test?
当然有  只是一直没有任何理由
Of course I did. I just never had any reason
去查看管道或表层的外部区域
to look at any areas outside of the pipeline or the cortex.
这栋楼很大  有很多地方
It's a big building. Lots of places
可以让威尔斯藏东西
for Wells to hide something.
怎么了
What is that?
这不应该出现在那里
That shouldn't be there.
这附近侦测到更多的放射强度
I'm picking up more activity around here.
超光速粒子
Tachyons.
这里
There.
天呐
Oh, my God.
伙计们
Guys.
《中城时报》
闪电侠失踪  消失于危机之中
搞什么啊
What the frak?
2024年4月25日